Lead Web Developer - JS + .NET

Swann Le Vigouroux, 19 bd Aiglin - 13004 Marseille - France • 06.41.584.582 • le.vigouroux.swann@gmail.com

PROFILE

>_ console.log (`Hello \${YOU}`);

I am a senior Web Developer who loves to play with new technologies. I work every day to improve my team's skills and mine. I can't imagine being in a team who does not like to share and spread knowledge around.

In my career, years spent in Toronto were really important. I have learnt to love even more our field by being around great people making the Web. And by being in the middle of younger developers in a thirst for knowledge.

I want to spend my energy to enable this enthusiastic work environment everywhere I could work for.

https://swannlv.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/swannlv

- Specialized in Web (I have done software, mobile & image analysis)
- Modern Javacript & Microsoft technologies
- Love learning and sharing
- Certified Scrum Master
- Worked in an English speaking city for 3 years

```
var skills = {
2
      languages: ["JavaScript ES6", "C#", "C++"],
      javascript: [ "Vue.js", "Webpack", "jQuery", "Angular.js", "Node.js"],
5
3
      dotNet: [ "dotnet core", "Azure", "MVC", "WebForms" ],
4
      mobile: ["Xamarin", "Blackberry WebWorks", "Bootstrap", "jQuery Mobile"],
6
      html5: ["WebGL", "WebRTC", "WebAudio"],
7
      software: [ "MFC", "OpenGL", "Silverlight", "Qt" ],
      tools: ["Visual Studio", "Git", "Cloud9 online IDE", "Resharper"],
      dataBases: [ "MS SQL", "MySql", "Redis" "Agility CMS" ]
10 };
```

WORK EXPERIENCE

```
Feb.2016 - Now
CMA CGM (with Altran), Marseille, France
```

Lead JS and .Net Developer

- Leading the technical side of Freddie (5 developers), the new ECommerce platform (JS ES6 + .Net):
 - Javascript architect, bringing innovation to the stack. Creation of mercury.js, which goal is to share in-house web components across the different teams of CMA CGM: webpack, vue.js, babel, etc ...
 - o Scrum Master
- ECommerce platform (MUST):
 - In charge of security and performances improvements
 - o C#, MS SQL, Oracle, Kendo, Knockout.js, ...

Jul.2015 - Feb.2016 : Back to France Freelance, Marseille, France

Mainly Dotnet and Azure work

- Built new features for wineven.com, C#, Entity, Azure, jQuery, MVC
- Built Xamarin app + Azure Mobile App for NCC Partners

Apr.2013 - Jun.2015

Union Creative (ex Trapeze Media), Toronto, Canada Lead C#.Net Developer - Creative Technologist

- Revamped Shoppers Drug Mart main .Net website (making coexist Webforms pages with the new MVC architecture)
- Managed a team of 2 to 6 developers + 2 QAs (inside of a pool of 20 developers):
 code reviews, mentoring, improving knowledge sharing
- Worked with creative teams to pitch new ideas to client related to brand new technologies, like Html5 features, Virtual Reality or electronics with Arduino
- Led the 30DaysOfBeauty .Net project and the weekly Support
- Improved internal processes:
 - Designed internal tools, for developers or project managers.
 - Made the team adopt Git with Visual Studio, and Team City (Continuous integration tool) to improve the releases.
- Create native mobile (iOS, Android, Windows Phone) apps demo using C#.Net only, with Xamarin.

Jan-Apr 2013

TRAPEZE MEDIA, Toronto, Canada

Intermediate C#.Net Developer

- Built the backend of several campaigns for Shoppers Drugmart, like:
 - Beauty Boutique, Heart Health, Innovative Products, Valentine's Day, ...
- Manage the support of the different websites and portal of Shoppers Drug Mart:
 - www1.shoppersdrugmart.ca
 - www.shoppershealthcareportal.org
 - www.drugcoverage.ca
 - www.sanis.com

Oct.2012 - Jan.2013

THROW AWAY GAMES, Toronto, Canada

Applications Developer

- Developed the Blackberry version of "AisleTracker", a single-page shopping tracker application, using Webworks platform and: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, Google Maps API.
- Started the built of a future big video platform (php mvc framework, javascript, ajax, mysql).

Oct.2009 - Aug.2012

ANYWARE VIDEO (Video Software Editor) – Marseille, France Software Engineer

- Evolved and maintained 24/7 Video Broadcast and Capture solutions for TV channels in C#.Net and C++.
- Charged of developing and managing the porting of the MFC Uis to Web
 Applications. Delivered the exact streaming Web Application that our biggest clients
 imagined, using their strong participation in an Agile environment (C++ to C#
 Asp.Net).
- Built a stream video player web application with JavaScript (Asp.Net , C#, Ajax, Windows Media Services).
- Integrated complex and sensitive systems at TV channels. Wrote and organized all the procedures from start to end: Determined Activities, Performed Installation & Tests, Certified the System, Validation Reports.
- Defined, designed, developed and delivered many high quality software systems under tight deadlines.
- Provided user training and real time support. Managed trainees and helped them to be part of the team.

Mar-Sep 2009

KAOLAB (Advanced Image Processing) – Marseille, France Software Engineer Intern

- Built new features of the Intelligent Video Surveillance solution including the IP video cameras support.
- Developed the calendar records programming (C++).
- Added new features to the video player (C++).

EDUCATION

2009 - Master's Degree - Computer Science in Image Processing Mediterranean University - Marseille, France

Software Engineering, 2D/3D, Medical Imaging, Computer-Aided Design, Visualization and Image Producing

2007 - Bachelor's Degree - Electrical Engineering and Industrial Computing Aix-Marseille University - Marseille, France

Electronics, Signal Processing, Computer Systems, Electromechanical and Automation

Skills

Dev skills: https://swannlv-skills.herokuapp.com

Languages

English, French

Old Personal Projects

- { WebAudio / WebGL } Demo Project (Javascript HTML5): swannlv.herokuapp.com
- > Control your spaceship to play with the music <
- { WebRTC / WebGL } Demo Project (Javascript HTML5 Node.js): pongrtc.herokuapp.com
- > Play Pong 3D online with a friend, just « moving your head » in front of your webcam

Super Resolution Image Analysis (C++) for the Scientific Police's Laboratory - Marseille, France

It creates an improved resolution image fusing information from low resolution images from video cameras

References

Available upon request